renewcanceltv.com 2019-03-21

# Privacy Policy | RenewCancelTV

## **RenewCancelTV Privacy Policy & GDPR Compliance**

 **Here we provide a clear and complete guide and your personal data, how we use it, how long we retain it and measures we take to keep your data safe and secure.**

RenewCancelTV.com takes your privacy _**very**_ seriously and is committed to protecting your privacy on its web sites. We strive to take the bare minimum information necessary to provide our services. We do not disclose personally identifiable information about our visitors, other than described below.

##  **1\. Who We Are**

We are RenewCancelTV.com (“[renewcanceltv.com](https://renewcanceltv.com/)“), an independent TV entertainment and news website. We provide historic and up-to-date news on the status of TV shows, specifically renewal and cancellation news and information.

##  **2\. What Personal Data We Collect and Why We Collect It**

 **2.1. Comments**

RenewCancelTV offers users the possibility to leave individual comments on individual posts/articles on our website. Our website is built using WordPress. We use the native WordPress comments system.

If you leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also your IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Users must consent that they want to leave a comment on the site by clicking “Post Comment” button. We have a comments section underneath articles on the site to allow users the opportunity to share their commentary on the topic in question. Comments are completely optional.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar (the display picture next to comments) service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your display picture (if you have one) is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

We use Akismet (WordPress module) to keep spam under control and prevent malicious content by filtering out spam comments. The information we collected includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL, along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself.Please see their privacy policy [here](https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/).

You may request rectification or removal (erasure) of your comment at any time by contacting us on the following email address: [[email protected]](https://renewcanceltv.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We will use your request to identify your comment and rectify or remove it, as per your instructions within 72 hours.

Should you have any further requests concerning your comments or data, please do not hesitate to contact us using [[email protected]](https://renewcanceltv.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We are more than happy to assist you in providing access and information relating to your data, where technically feasible and when doing so does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

 **2.2. Email Contact**

Information submitted to us by email are sent to our website email, hosted by Gmail (owned by Google). Google adheres to the EU “Privacy Shield” policy. More information about this is available [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy/frameworks).

We retain these submissions for user service purposes only (e.g. to deal with and respond to user queries) and they are never used for marketing purposes or shared with third parties.

 **2.3. Cookies**

Many Internet sites and servers use cookies (“cookies”). Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a character string through which Internet pages and servers can be assigned to the specific Internet browser in which the cookie was stored. This allows visited Internet sites and servers to differentiate the individual browser of the data subject from other Internet browsers that contain other cookies. A specific Internet browser can be recognized and identified using the unique cookie ID.

Cookies can be helpful as they allow websites to recognize a user’s device, therefore saving you time and providing a more user-friendly experience that would not be possible without cookies being set. For more information on cookies, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Practical example of cookies in action: If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies, by clicking the checkbox to confirm. These cookies are for convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

The data subject may, at any time, disable the setting of cookies through our website by means of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. Please bear in mind, that if the data subject deactivates the setting of cookies in the Internet browser used, not all functions of our website may be entirely usable.

 **2.4. Third Party Cookies**

 **DoubleClick DART Cookie  **

Our web site uses third party ad servers (e.g. DoubleClick) to serve the advertisements that you see on some pages of our web site. DoubleClick may use cookies to help serve their advertisements. For more information on DoubleClick’s cookie policy, please click [here](https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/2839090).

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on renewcanceltv.com. Google may use ad personalisation to make ads more useful to our users outside the EU. We have Google ad personalisation disabled for EU users. Please read [Google’s privacy and terms page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) to learn more about how Google uses personalisation, information from sites or apps that use its services, and how you can control the information collected by Google on our site and other sites like ours.
  * The DART cookie enables Google to serve ads to users based on their visit to renewcanceltv.com and other websites across the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Please see below for the list of our advertising partners which may use cookies and web beacons on our site:

  * Google Adsense ([privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites))
  * Amazon ([privacy policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496#GUID-1B2BDAD4-7ACF-4D7A-8608-CBA6EA897FD3__SECTION_D17374D6EE5B4077946965351E11175C); [GDPR policy](https://advertising.amazon.com/ad-specs/en/policy/gdpr?ref_=blog-inpage))
  * Media.net ([privacy policy](https://www.media.net/en/privacy-policy); also see [ad preference policy](https://www.media.net/en/adchoices))
  * Sovrn ([privacy policy](https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/))
  * Taboola ([privacy policy](https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy))
  * Ezoic ([privacy policy](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/renewcanceltv.com))

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on RenewCancelTV.com send directly to your web browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (e.g. cookies, JavaScript or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

RenewCancelTV.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

Please consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices.RenewCancelTV’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

Should you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser or device settings. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

RenewCancelTV.com will not rent or sell personally identifying information to anyone. Other than its operators RenewCancelTV.com discloses personally identifying information only when required to do so – for example, if requested by the law or if RenewCancelTV.com believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the rights of RenewCancelTV.com, its network web sites, partners, or the public at large.

Our site also uses the following cookies:

  * WordPress logged-in cookies – As above, if you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. This is performed by clicking on the checkbox above the “Post Comment” button.
  * Google Analytics cookies – These are set for monitoring and tracking the behavior of visitors on the site. This helps us to improve measure performance and improve the site.
  * WP Rocket cookies – These are used by WP Rocket cache plugin to monitor referrer and user identification for caching purposes.
  * WP Polls cookies – These are used by WP Polls plugin to provide secure polls functionality based on user identification.
  * Toolset plugin cookies – Used to provide functionality related to our TV show listings.

 **2.5. Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, tweets, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

Such embedded content services may include:

  * Twitter
  * Facebook
  * Instagram
  * YouTube

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

 **2.6. Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to measure visitors’ behavior and measure site performance. We do this to monitor site performance (articles, pages) and improve the quality of service we offer.  To learn about Google Analytics’ opt-outs, [please visit their policy document](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881).

We also use the following analytics packages to analyse site performance and monitoring:

  * Jetpack – Provides statistics regarding site traffic and visitor usage – this includes comments, comment username, comment email address, comment IP address, pages visited, pages clicked). We use this information to monitor, measure and improve the site for our visitors. Jetpack is owned and controlled by Automatic, which is GDPR compliant. You can find more information about their privacy policy [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).
  * Cloudflare – Provides insight to our website traffic, visitor analytics (pages visited, real-time visits, Geo-location), allowing us to monitor threats and search engine crawlers. You can read Cloudflare’s GDPR compliance statement [here](https://www.cloudflare.com/gdpr/introduction/).

 **2.7. Newsletters**

We offer web visitors the opportunity to subscribe to our weekly renew/cancel TV newsletter. This is a free service which subscribers can opt out of (unsubscribe) from at any time. To unsubscribe from our newsletter simply click the “unsubscribe” link attached to each email containing our newsletter, or write to us using [[email protected]](https://renewcanceltv.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We will proceed to remove (delete) your email and data from our newsletter lists within 72 hours.

When you subscribe to our newsletter, your data (such as email address, IP address, date of sign up, date of opt-in, geo-location) is stored on Aweber servers. Aweber is a leading email marketing service which abides by data protection and privacy laws (GDPR). You can view their privacy policy [here](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm).

  * We use your data to send the newsletters you have requested to your inbox.
  * We use your data to notify you of information related to the service you have signed up for e.g. to inform you of important policy changes or that a service has been suspended.
  * We use your data to unsubscribe or delete you from our list.
  * We use your data to measure (e.g. monitor overall newsletter opens, bounce rate) and improve the quality of service we offer.

We do not store your data on renewcanceltv.com servers. We provide a means for your to sign up, through a sign up form located on renewcanceltv.com, which invites you to confirm your interest in receiving our newsletters (upon sign-up, and again through email confirmation) before subscribing your to our list. Once you confirm to us that you want to receive our newsletters – by entering your email address in the newsletter form and clicking on the sign up button – you will be redirected to a confirmation page confirming your subscription. You will then receive a confirmation email as a means of double checking that you requested to be added to our list. Your data (email address, IP, date/time of sign-up) is stored on Aweber servers for the sole purpose of sending you the newsletters for which you have requested, to contact you regarding the service you have requested and for analytical purposes (to measure and improve the performance of our service).

We do not sell your data to third parties. By subscribing to our newsletter list, we provide subscribers with renew/cancel TV news and information, and give each subscriber the opportunity to unsubscribe and/or have their data deleted at any time.

##  **3\. How Long We Retain Your Data**

If you leave a comment on the site, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely or until you ask us to remove it. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. If your comment is held in moderation, it must be approved by a site administrator before appearing on the site. Should you wish to remove or edit a comment you have made on the site, please issue a request using [[email protected]](https://renewcanceltv.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

We do not currently allow user registration to the site.

Google Analytics records are held for 26 months, this is to enable use to monitor and track site performance and improvements.

Emails sent to our website email account are held indefinitely or until you ask use to delete them. This is to provide support services and requests from users, so that we may reply to and authenticate user requests.

##  **4\. Who We Share Your Data With**

RenewCancelTV.com shall never sell or transfer your personally identifiable information such as email, name, etc, to unaffiliated third parties.

However, some data is transferred and/or stored with third-party services we use, such cloud-based services and newsletter services. This is only done as a way to provide you with a high-quality service and user experience.

Here are the services we use to improve your experience:

  * InMotionHosting – our webserver which hosts renewcanceltv.com; keeps it online and accessible to visitors; stores our databases, files and themes; takes limited site backups. InMotionHosting also controls renewcanceltv.com billing data, that is the costs of hosting the site.
  * Aweber – newsletter service used to collect, store and delete subscriber contact details (such as email), deliver our weekly email newsletters to subscribers, who can opt-out at any time, and measure the effectiveness of our newsletters (clickthrough rates, bounce rates). Aweber is GDPR compliant, you can read their privacy policy [here](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm).

Our website reserves the right to perform statistical analysis of user behavior and characteristics in order to measure the activity and interest in areas of the site to further improve our website.

## 5\. Additional Data Protection Provisions

 **5.1. Facebook**

On certain pages, we may integrate components of the enterprise Facebook. Facebook is a social network.

A social network is a place for social meetings on the Internet, an online community, which usually allows users to communicate with each other and interact in a virtual space. A social network may serve as a platform for the exchange of opinions and experiences, or enable the Internet community to provide personal or business-related information. Facebook allows social network users to include the creation of private profiles, upload photos, and network through friend requests.

The operating company of Facebook is Facebook, Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, United States. If a person lives outside of the United States or Canada, the controller is the Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet website, which is operated by the controller and into which a Facebook component (Facebook plug-ins) was integrated, the web browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download display of the corresponding Facebook component from Facebook through the Facebook component. An overview of all the Facebook Plug-ins may be accessed under https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/. During the course of this technical procedure, Facebook is made aware of what specific sub-site of our website was visited by the data subject.

If you are logged in at the same time on Facebook, Facebook detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject—and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site—which specific sub-site of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Facebook component and associated with the respective Facebook account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the Facebook buttons integrated into our website, e.g. the “Like” button, or if the data subject submits a comment, then Facebook matches this information with the personal Facebook user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

Facebook always receives, through the Facebook component, information about a visit to our website by the data subject, whenever the data subject is logged in at the same time on Facebook during the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the data subject clicks on the Facebook component or not. If such a transmission of information to Facebook is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their Facebook account before a call-up to our website is made.

The data protection guideline published by Facebook, which is available at https://facebook.com/about/privacy/, provides information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by Facebook. In addition, it is explained there what setting options Facebook offers to protect the privacy of the data subject. In addition, different configuration options are made available to allow the elimination of data transmission to Facebook. These applications may be used by the data subject to eliminate a data transmission to Facebook.

 **5.2. Google Adsense**

RenewCancelTV uses Google AdSense. Google AdSense is an online service which allows the placement of advertising on third-party sites. Google AdSense is based on an algorithm that selects advertisements displayed on third-party sites to match with the content of the respective third-party site. Google AdSense allows an interest-based targeting of the Internet user, which is implemented by means of generating individual user profiles.

The operating company of Google’s AdSense component is Alphabet Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

The purpose of Google’s AdSense component is the integration of advertisements on our website. Google AdSense places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Alphabet Inc. is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google AdSense component is integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google AdSense component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Alphabet Inc. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Alphabet Inc. gains knowledge of personal data, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Alphabet Inc., inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks and subsequently create commission settlements.

The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Alphabet Inc. from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. Additionally, cookies already in use by Alphabet Inc. may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.

Furthermore, Google AdSense also uses so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic that is embedded in web pages to enable a log file recording and a log file analysis through which a statistical analysis may be performed. Based on the embedded tracking pixels, Alphabet Inc. is able to determine if and when a website was opened by a data subject, and which links were clicked on by the data subject. Tracking pixels serve, inter alia, to analyze the flow of visitors on a website.

Through Google AdSense, personal data and information—which also includes the IP address, and is necessary for the collection and accounting of the displayed advertisements—is transmitted to Alphabet Inc. in the United States of America. These personal data will be stored and processed in the United States of America. The Alphabet Inc. may disclose the collected personal data through this technical procedure to third parties.

Google AdSense is further explained under the following link https://www.google.com/intl/en/adsense/start/.

As mentioned in this privacy policy, and for clarifity, we also use the following advertising services: Amazon, Media.net, Sovrn and Taboola.

#### 5.3. Google Analytics (anonymized)

RenewCancelTV has integrated the component of Google Analytics (with the anonymizer function). Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, gathering, and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects, inter alia, data about the website from which a person has come (the so-called referrer), which sub-pages were visited, or how often and for what duration a sub-page was viewed. Web analytics are mainly used for the optimization of a website and in order to carry out a cost-benefit analysis of Internet advertising.

The operator of the Google Analytics component is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

For the web analytics through Google Analytics the controller uses the application “_gat. _anonymizeIp”. By means of this application the IP address of the Internet connection of the data subject is abridged by Google and anonymised when accessing our websites from a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting State to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

The purpose of the Google Analytics component is to analyze the traffic on our website. Google uses the collected data and information, inter alia, to evaluate the use of our website and to provide online reports, which show the activities on our websites, and to provide other services concerning the use of our Internet site for us.

Google Analytics places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Google is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google Analytics component was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google Analytics component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Google. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Google gains knowledge of personal information, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Google, inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks, and subsequently create commission settlements.

The cookie is used to store personal information, such as the access time, the location from which the access was made, and the frequency of visits of our website by the data subject. With each visit to our Internet site, such personal data, including the IP address of the Internet access used by the data subject, will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. These personal data are stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may pass these personal data collected through the technical procedure to third parties.

The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Google Analytics from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. In addition, cookies already in use by Google Analytics may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.

In addition, the data subject has the possibility of objecting to a collection of data that are generated by Google Analytics, which is related to the use of this website, as well as the processing of this data by Google and the chance to preclude any such. For this purpose, the data subject must download a browser add-on under the link https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and install it. This browser add-on tells Google Analytics through a JavaScript, that any data and information about the visits of Internet pages may not be transmitted to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-ons is considered an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the data subject is later deleted, formatted, or newly installed, then the data subject must reinstall the browser add-ons to disable Google Analytics. If the browser add-on was uninstalled by the data subject or any other person who is attributable to their sphere of competence, or is disabled, it is possible to execute the reinstallation or reactivation of the browser add-ons.

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ and under http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html. Google Analytics is further explained under the following Link https://www.google.com/analytics/.

 **5.4. Instagram**

On certain pages of our website, we may integrate components of the service Instagram. Instagram is a service that may be qualified as an audiovisual platform, which allows users to share photos and videos, as well as disseminate such data in other social networks.

The operating company of the services offered by Instagram is Instagram LLC, 1 Hacker Way, Building 14 First Floor, Menlo Park, CA, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which an Instagram component (Insta button) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to the download of a display of the corresponding Instagram component of Instagram. During the course of this technical procedure, Instagram becomes aware of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time on Instagram, Instagram detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject—and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site—which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Instagram component and is associated with the respective Instagram account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the Instagram buttons integrated on our website, then Instagram matches this information with the personal Instagram user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

Instagram receives information via the Instagram component that the data subject has visited our website provided that the data subject is logged in at Instagram at the time of the call to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the Instagram button or not. If such a transmission of information to Instagram is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she can prevent this by logging off from their Instagram account before a call-up to our website is made.

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Instagram may be retrieved under https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388 and https://www.instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/.

 **5.5. Twitter**

On certain pages of RenewCancelTV, we may integrate components of Twitter. Twitter is a multilingual, publicly-accessible microblogging service on which users may publish and spread so-called ‘tweets,’ e.g. short messages, which are limited to 140 characters. These short messages are available for everyone, including those who are not logged on to Twitter. The tweets are also displayed to so-called followers of the respective user. Followers are other Twitter users who follow a user’s tweets. Furthermore, Twitter allows you to address a wide audience via hashtags, links or retweets.

The operating company of Twitter is Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a Twitter component (Twitter button) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding Twitter component of Twitter. Further information about the Twitter buttons is available under https://about.twitter.com/de/resources/buttons. During the course of this technical procedure, Twitter gains knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject. The purpose of the integration of the Twitter component is a retransmission of the contents of this website to allow our users to introduce this web page to the digital world and increase our visitor numbers.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time on Twitter, Twitter detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Twitter component and associated with the respective Twitter account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the Twitter buttons integrated on our website, then Twitter assigns this information to the personal Twitter user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

Twitter receives information via the Twitter component that the data subject has visited our website, provided that the data subject is logged in on Twitter at the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the Twitter component or not. If such a transmission of information to Twitter is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their Twitter account before a call-up to our website is made.

The applicable data protection provisions of Twitter may be accessed under https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en.

 **5.6. YouTube**

On certain pages we may integrate components of YouTube. YouTube is an Internet video portal that enables video publishers to set video clips and other users free of charge, which also provides free viewing, review and commenting on them. YouTube allows you to publish all kinds of videos, so you can access both full movies and TV broadcasts, as well as music videos, trailers, and videos made by users via the Internet portal.

The operating company of YouTube is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, UNITED STATES. The YouTube, LLC is a subsidiary of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a YouTube component (YouTube video) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding YouTube component. Further information about YouTube may be obtained under https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/en/. During the course of this technical procedure, YouTube and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If you are logged in on YouTube, YouTube recognizes with each call-up to a sub-page that contains a YouTube video, which specific sub-page of our Internet site was visited by the data subject. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube account of the data subject.

YouTube and Google will receive information through the YouTube component that the data subject has visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call to our website is logged in on YouTube; this occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on a YouTube video or not. If such a transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desirable for the data subject, the delivery may be prevented if the data subject logs off from their own YouTube account before a call-up to our website is made.

YouTube’s data protection provisions, available at https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/, provide information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.

 **5.7. Amazon Affiliation**

RenewCancelTV.com participates in the Amazon affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn small advertising fees by linking to Amazon.com, where appropriate.

## 6.0. What rights you have over your data

If you have left comments on this site or have subscribed to our newsletter, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## 7.0. How We Protect Your Data

We’re serious about protecting the security of your personal information and safeguarding our website to ensure it is secure for our users.

We protect your data through a number of measures, as outlined below:

  * We use a secure server to host our site.
  * We use secure and complex passwords for our server and website.
  * We regularly change system and administrator passwords.
  * Our site uses SSL and HTTPS. This encrypts your communications with our server so that personal identifiable information is never captured by third parties without permission. You can read more about SSL and HTTPS [here](https://www.instantssl.com/ssl-certificate-products/https.html).
  * We perform regular site backups. Daily backups are performed in a secure environment. We also perform backups through an integrated WordPress service called Vaultpress, which connects from our site to its servers, to perform daily backups. Vaultpress does not collect or track personal identifiable information.
  * Cloudflare. We use this as a content delivery network for our site. Cloudflare scans for, identifies and blocks threats, provides advanced DDoS protection and mitigation.
  * We constantly review our security policies and engage in staff training in data protection.
  * We use as few plugins and external services as necessary to run the site and perform its functions.
  * We do not use contact forms on the site, further reducing the amount of data we request from our visitors. Instead, we invite users to contact us directly through email using [[email protected]](https://renewcanceltv.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

##  **8.0. Period for which the personal data will be stored**

The criteria used to determine the period of storage of personal data is the respective statutory retention period. After expiration of that period, the corresponding data is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of the contract or the initiation of a contract.

## 9.0. What Data Breach Procedures We Have In Place

Should a breach occur, our system administrators will analyse the breach and enact our breach procedure. We will attempt to locate and sanitize the area(s) affected as quickly and thoroughly as possible. We will perform server and site-level scans to ensure to breach has been contained. In the event that user data is compromised, we will notify our users through a post on the website (or via email, should the breach relate to our newsletter subscribers) within 72 hours, explaining what has happened, how we’re resolving the issue, and what we will do to further safeguard user data.

Following the breach, we will hold a staff meeting to discuss how we can improve security on the site.

##  **10\. Existence of automated decision-making**

As a responsible entity, we do not use automatic decision-making or profiling.

##  **11.0. Privacy Policy Changes**

RenewCancelTV.com may update its privacy policy from time to time at RenewCancelTV.com discretion. RenewCancelTV.com encourages visitors to regularly check this page for any changes, updates or amendments to the RenewCancelTV.com privacy policy. Your continued use of RenewCancelTV.com after any change will constitute acceptance of such change.

If you would like to speak to RenewCancelTV.com about our Privacy Policy, please contact us using info [@] RenewCancelTV.com.

Attribution for this Privacy Policy goes to the [Automatic Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/), which is available under the[ Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.5 Generic License](http://go2.wordpress.com/?id=725X1342&site=automattic.wordpress.com&url=http%3A%2F%2Fcreativecommons.org%2Flicenses%2Fby-sa%2F2.5%2F&sref=http%3A%2F%2Fautomattic.com%2Fprivacy%2F), and the [External Data Protection Officers](https://dg-datenschutz.de/services/external-data-protection-officer/?lang=en) that was developed in cooperation with RC GmbH, which sells [used notebooks](http://remarketing.company/) and the [Media Law Lawyers](https://www.wbs-law.de/eng/practice-areas/media-law/) from WBS-LAW.
